I found myself lost and alone on this journey
Though my heart wandered far and wide, I could move not an inch
But now I can depart for any distant land
Now that we've met on this road
Even the unfamiliar songs of travelers
Can spark nostalgia in me when I'm with you
If the world we dreamed of exists somewhere,
Then let's go search for it beyond the wind
Through chilling dawns,
Through arid noons,
Through shivering nights,
Let's go see what lies at the end
How many did you eat?
Seventeen.
No, eighteen.
No, maybe nineteen?
And how many are left?
Forget about it.
I need to know.
You already know!
Tell me anyway.
Eight...
Eight?
Eighty-one!
It'll be fine if I just eat them all, right?
Do you think you'll be able to eat all of them?
Yes!
I'm Holo, the wise wolf of Yoitz!
You don't need to be so obstinate.
Who's obstinate?
What's the real truth?
It is the real truth.
What's the real real truth?
It's the real real truth!
What's the real, real, real truth?
It's the real, real, real truth!
Actually, I'm getting sick of them.
I'd imagine so.
Even if they're your favorite food, you had twenty yesterday and almost as many today.
But...
But I'll show you I can eat them all!
You don't have to be so stubborn about it.
You may be tired of the raw fruit,
but there are lots of other ways to eat apples.
Other ways? What other ways?
D-Don't ridicule me!
I've never heard of apples being baked before!
You've seriously never eaten apple pie?
Such a thing really exists?
Yeah, you bake it in a pan with dough.
And if you do that, it becomes chewy...
This isn't a good example,
but it's as if they started rotting.
But just like things taste good right before they go bad, baked apples are extremely tasty, too.
When you eat fresh apples, they moisten your dry throat.
But baked apples are so sweet that they make your throat dry.
But I'm sure you're tired of sweet food.
So, we'll have a change of pace for dinner and have salted meat or fish.
Which would you like?
Meat!
What happened to that girl who looked
like she couldn't eat any more?
If it is meat, it's a different story.
Come on!
Hey, don't forget that you need to take care of these apples.
Don't worry.
I have confidence I can eat them all after what I just heard!
Well, I have some business too, so let's go.
Yeah!
I'm treating you to a change in mood so you won't get sick of me.
When I swallow your treats whole, I tend to get heartburn.
Do you want me to tell you that was clever?
I wouldn't mind.
Wolf and the Tail of Happiness
Hmm, well...
It's just...
How should I say it? You...
You really do look like a nun.
Indeed. It's convenient for traveling, isn't it?
I suppose.
People are as strange as ever, treating each other so differently
based on whether they're wearing a specific piece of cloth or not.
There are times when it's convenient
for wolves to wear sheep's clothing too, right?
You're right.
If I wore rabbit's fur, I'm sure you'd fall into my trap instantly.
Then I guess I should carry some apples as protection in case I get caught.
Just when I finally forgot about apples...
But...
In your case, looking too much
like a nun could lead to problems.
Like what?
Nuns don't drink during the day under any circumstances.
That just makes me an amazing nun, right?
And nuns don't talk like that, either.
I beg your pardon, sir.
In all seriousness, there will be places where dressing as a nun would be a bad idea once we head north.
So what should we do?
So, uh...
Well, it'd make things safer for you
to have a set of clothes like a city girl's.
Let's go and buy some before we eat, then.
If our minds are on business,
our meal won't be as good.
Th-Thank you. I'm glad I don't have to try and persuade you.
Were you thinking I'd say we should eat and drink first?
I won't get distracted by food that easily!
I wonder about that.
I can hardly hamper your attempts to look out for my feelings.
Did you really think I wouldn't notice after you came up with
such a grand, important reason just to buy me some clothes?
Well, I'll cast aside my sheepishness and let you buy them.
It's going to be a cold, cold winter, after all.
Well, you don't have to cast it all aside.
Wh-What's wrong?
I have no money.
You...
That's not what I meant.
I'm saying I don't have small change.
Better too big than too small, as they say.
You can simply use that money, no?
There's also the saying about skinning a rabbit with a meat cleaver.
If I used this money at a clothing store,
I can't imagine how annoyed they'd be.
I see.
But are gold coins really worth so much?
Of course.
For example, a Lumione gold coin is currently worth thirty-five Trenni silver coins.
If you live humbly, one silver coin can last seven days.
And it's worth thirty-five times that.
That's quite something.
However...
The store said that these clothes were worth two gold coins.
Unlike apples, wouldn't clothes
be something you'd buy with gold coins?
If that were true, most of the people in the city would be naked.
I'm sure the merchant who sold those clothes
must've been quite worried that you'd even pay.
Were these that expensive?
Of course.
So choose some shabby-looking clothes when we buy them.
I'm Holo, the wise wolf of Yoitz!
If I wear something shabby, it'll tarnish my name!
They say that if you are truly beautiful,
then anything should look good on you.
I suppose the money exchange is the next—
Oh, we're going to exchange money?
Then we're going to that bridge, right?
Hey, come on!
Hurry up and walk.
I want to go drinking soon.
Lumione, you say?
Today's market price for it
is thirty-four Trenni silver coins on the dot.
And the handling charge?
Ten Lute coins, or thirty Trie coins.
I'll pay in Lute coins.
Understood. Well then...
Oh, please be careful.
If you drop them, they'll belong to whoever picks them up off the street.
Weiz.
What?
I'm the customer.
Leave the gold coin there. I'm busy right now.
Even though you're not even treating your precious customers properly?
Of course!
It's more important that this precious little lady doesn't drop any coins.
Isn't that right?
My, that makes me happy.
But, dear sir...
What is it?
There are just too many coins for my hand to hold.
That's why my hands are there, Holo-san.
My, but we can't do this.
You won't be able to use your precious hands.
Not at all! I'll gladly use my hands so that these coins won't fall from your own.
It does not trouble me in any way.
That is because my chest burns for you with a fire that I cannot bear myself,
and I know that you'll help me bear it in turn!
Weiz!
Did you forget the basics of being a money exchanger?
Silver in a bag, gold in a chest.
Only crude copper coins should be kept in hand!
Geez.
Keeping such a good girl to yourself is an act against God.
Haven't you heard the passage that says to share what bread you can offer?
You want me to share?
There's no lending at the money exchange table.
Only a full exchange or no exchange.
If you take her, the debt she
owes me comes with her,
so you need to show
me you're ready for that.
I can't possibly place a price on you!
Just how can you say that, you corrupt merchant!
The scale in my heart is still tilting back and forth right now.
But please, believe that it is not tilting because of the weight of gold coins.
Of course! Of course, I believe you.
You really are a wicked man,
to touch a tilting scale with your hands.
Holo-san...
Come on, let's get going.
H-Hey, Lawrence.
You came to exchange some gold coins,
so are you going shopping or something?
That's right.
Prices seem like they're going to rise.
So the faster, the better.
Bye for now.
Do money exchangers work even when the sun sets?
Heaven forbid! You can be sure that money exchangers who use scales after the sun sets are swindlers!
And of course, I'm no swindler.
You heard him.
Once I buy clothes, I'll be going to the tavern early.
You can come if you want when you're done working.
Of course, my brother!
It's the usual tavern, right?
It's scary to get drunk in a tavern you don't know.
All right!
Right away! I'll really be there soon!
That was as fun as I thought it'd be.
You'll regret it later if you get him too serious.
Regret it?
He'll follow you around.
You're already following me.
Unlike you, he knows he is playing a game.
It's fun teasing you,
but I want to play with some smart males sometimes.
Both of us know that it's a game,
so could you not act so serious about it?
I'll start blushing, you know.
Well, although that Weiz fellow is more of an eloquent talker than you,
I've lived long enough to know that nothing is so untrustworthy as the words we say.
I'm sure a man of business like yourself would understand that to some degree.
Yeah. I'd tell any lie as long as it brought me profit.
They won't work on me, though.
All right, let's go shopping for clothes.
Hey!
You've twice missed your chance to grasp the happiness God granted.
If you don't grasp it next time,
the tail of happiness might escape you.
Hey, what do you mean?
Hey, Holo! Wait for me!
That one right there is forty Lute.
It's quite durable for that price.
I'm heading north, so could you find some things that'll be cheap and warm for the two of us?
What is your budget?
Two Trenni coins.
Please leave it to me.
A set of robes, two blankets...
And would something like this be fine?
Let's see...
As you can see, I'm a merchant.
On my travels, I became friends with the Milone Company here.
Oh? With Milone?
Right, so I might stop by a few times a year from now on.
Oh, is that so?
Then let me add another blanket along with this robe.
Of course, they've been smoked,
so I guarantee that they'll repel bugs for two years.
Didn't we come to buy clothes for me?
That's right.
Are you telling me to wear that?
Do you want to try and fight the cold off with that robe alone?
If you are upset about my spending your
money without asking, just say so.
I'm Holo, the wise wolf.
I'm smart and I have good business sense, but my nose is sharp too!
The day I wear that, my nose will turn up!
I thought having you suffer a bit
might fix that twisted personality of yours.
Don't get angry.
I'll let you in on the secret later.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes?
Do you have any nice clothes for women?
Clothes for women?
Something that won't cause much trouble in northern cities,
in about her size.
Very well. Please wait just a moment.
How about this?
It's a court attendant's dress that was bought from another shop.
I don't want something that gaudy.
It doesn't suit you?
I want something simpler and easy to change into.
Then...
Sir, how about that?
Excuse me?
I see!
You're quite the person to have laid your eyes on this.
These articles were once worn by a noble.
Just look. The seams are sewn neatly, and it won't tear so easily.
What you should really be looking at is this walnut-colored cap.
Once you wear this over your shoulder
and wear this specially tailored triangular cap just like the servants at this noble's house,
you'll become the most envied girl in town just like that!
A rabbit?
Does it make you hungry?
I like this!
How much is it?
For the two of them, let's see...
Ten Trenni coins.
No, how about nine coins?
Very well.
In deference to the beautiful lady here, I'll make it eight coins.
Well, then...
If someone as cute as myself would show them off for all to see right here and now, would you make it seven coins?
V-Very well, I'll let you have it for seven coins.
Thank you.
Excuse me then.
What do you think?
Wonderful!
Paying one Trenni for this was a steal!
Were these clothes too expensive?
No, seven coins for those is quite good.
You still had enough confidence to drive the price down?
I thought if I picked the kind of clothes you are carrying,
we could have purchased them for one
tenth of the price we paid for these.
Yeah.
I actually thought it would've cost more, so don't worry.
Okay.
As long as you temper your drinking later,
you'll make up for the seven coins right away.
I don't drink that much!
But still, the way you bargained with him was really cheap.
No matter how expert the
merchant is, he can't beat that.
All males are idiots, after all.
What are you going to do with that?
Taking it with you to the tavern?
No, not at all.
But the inn isn't this way.
Yeah, I won't be leaving it at the inn either.
I'm going to sell these at a different clothes shop.
We can buy some clothes for the cold when we head a bit further north.
You're going to sell them?
There's no point in keeping them
if we're not going to use them, right?
That's true, but will they sell high?
I'm not sure.
Seeing a profit would be difficult.
I'll probably have a bit of a loss.
You're still going to sell them if you have a loss?
You don't understand why?
Hold on, I'm thinking now.
Shall I tell you the secret?
I won't ask you to tell me!
But if you want to say it, then go ahead.
That said, it's nothing special,
and you did a better job after all.
This bunch of clothes is worth two coins.
For example, let's say we sell these
at a different store for half the price.
I'd have a loss of one coin.
Right.
But let's direct our attention to something else.
Something else?
That's right.
Anyone can tell at a glance that your robe is high grade, right?
My robe...
It's safe to say that a person wearing it wouldn't ever go to a shop like that.
So that shop owner wanted to have a good relationship with me since I was with you.
Now then, if you were him, what would you do?
I'd sell things cheap to leave a good impression.
That's right.
And what follows from that?
That owner lowered the price on these a bit.
Then he lowered the price on yours a lot.
We were the customers who'd taken two coins worth of these ragged clothes off his hands after all.
However, there's a huge gap between the two prices.
And what does that mean?
If we think about the total balance, we saved a lot.
Well done.
What a cheap trick. A completely cheap trick!
That trick?
Fool!
I'm amazed you even thought of that.
That's called business sense.
Though your brute force technique was better in the end.
Naturally.
Your shallow thinking can't beat my scheming.
You've said it now.
You think you can win?
Well, if you're confident about it,
maybe you could show me your skills when we go drinking.
When we go drinking?
Make sure you pay a high price for me, now.
Oh, I'll buy you, all right.
But the payment will be in apples.
You're pretty tough, too.
If you bake me, I might become a bit sweeter.
You're pretty well baked already.
Males baked with jealousy are too sweet to eat.
What about you, then?
Do you want to have a bite and see for yourself?
I'll think about it.
You grasped it properly the third time.
Next Episode: "Wolf and a Proper Balance."